newsi.us 2009-07-05

# SepticSystem.com -- Privacy Policy

| 

This privacy statement covers the site www.SepticSystem.com, and includes information on the following topics: 

  * What personally identifiable information SepticSystem.com collects.
  * What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.
  * What organization collects the information.
  * How SepticSystem.com uses the information.
  * With whom SepticSystem.com may share user information.
  * What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
  * What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under SepticSystem.com's control.
  * How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have any questions or concerns about this policy, please email us at privacy at septicsystem dot com. 

## Information Collection

SepticSystem.com is the sole owner of the information collected on www.SepticSystem.com. SepticSystem.com collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site. 

### Registration form

Many features on this web site require that a user register. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as email address and password). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which (s)he has expressed an interest. We may occasionally ask the user to provide contact, demographic or geographic information. This helps us to provide a more personalized experience on the site. 

### Order forms

We request information from the user on our order forms. A user must provide financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date and zip code). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user. 

## Information Use

### Profile

We store and gather information from cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their preferences and actions. Collected information is tied to a user's identity to provide offers and improved content. This profile is used to tailor a users visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

### Cookies

A cookie is a piece of data stored on a user's computer which allows us to track the user during their visit to our site. We use session cookies (rather than permanent cookies). Once a user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. If users rejects the cookie, they may still use our site, although they will not be able to access areas of the site which require login. 

Some of our business partners (ex: advertisers) may use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

### Third Party Advertising

The ads appearing on this Web site may be delivered to users by our web advertising partners. We do not pass personal information to those advertisers about our users -- although those advertisers may choose to use technologies that allow them to connect a user's presence on our site with the same user's presence on other sites. This is standard practice by some advertisers, and is in no way unique to SepticSystem.com. 

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by www.SepticSystem.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

### Log Files

Like most Web sites we record information about your session and write it to databases and log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses (which can be traced to your internet service provider (ISP), browser type, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, which pages you requested, etc. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track users' movements in particular and in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. This information allows us to link your ip address to any personally identifiable information that you have given us. 

## Communications from the Site

### Offers and Updates

We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter if they opt in to receive this information. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections. 

### Service Announcements

On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. 

### Customer Service

We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account. We reply via email or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

## Sharing

### Legal Disclaimer

Although we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. 

### Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)

We may share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information. 

### Third Party Intermediaries

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. This company does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

### Business Transitions

In the event SepticSystem.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. 

### Choice/Opt-out

Our users are given the opportunity to opt-out of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. 

Users who no longer wish to receive our promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or by emailing us at privacy at septicsystem dot com. 

### Links

This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, SepticSystem.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site. 

### Tell-A-Friend

If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. SepticSystem.com will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. SepticSystem.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email (and tracking the success of our referral program). 

### Security

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. 

We do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. Users' information is stored on our servers under password controls. Access to that information is granted to employees on a need-to-know basis. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, 

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to privacy at septicsystem dot com. 

### Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information

If a user's personally identifiable information (such as email) changes or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done by emailing Customer Support at support at septicsystem dot com. 

### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by posting a notice on our Web site for 30 days. 

### Contact Information

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: privacy at septicsystem dot com.
